Guide to the Kenneth Farrand Simpson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Kenneth Farrand Simpson papers
1900-1983
1923-1941
MS 92
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
14.5
(37 boxes and 4 reels of microfilm)
The papers consist of correspondence, political memoranda, campaign literature, and printed matter documenting Kenneth Simpson's career as chairman of the Republican County Committee in New York (1935-1940). The papers also include case and client files from Simpson's legal practice. The papers highlight Simpson's support for Fiorello LaGuardia in the 1936 New York mayoral campaign, his opposition to Thomas E. Dewey's candidacy for presidential nomination in 1940, and his own successful campaign for election to the United States House of Representatives from the Seventeenth Congressional District of New York in 1940.
Simpson, Kenneth F. (Kenneth Farrand), 1895-1941
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Helen Louise Seggerman, 1983
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Existence and Location of Copies
Scrapbooks in Series VI are available on microfilm (2,284 frames on 4 reels, 35 mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM121.
Biographical / Historical
Kenneth Farrand Simpson was born in New York City on May 4, 1895 into a socially prominent family. His father was a well-known throat specialist and professor of laryngology at Columbia's College of Physicians and Surgeons. Simpson attended Hill School and was a member of the Yale College Class of 1917. He served in the military during World War I and was stationed in France from June, 1918 until the summer of 1919. On his return to the United States, he entered the Harvard Law School and completed his LL.B. degree in 1922. He was admitted to the bar in the same year and began his legal practice in New York City.
Simpson initially joined the legal firm of Cadwalader, Wickersham & Taft, but in 1925, after becoming involved in Republican Party politics, Simpson was offered a position as assistant United States attorney for the Southern District of New York. At the time, the government was attempting to adjudicate a number of cases involving German-owned property which had been confiscated during World War I. Simpson became a specialist in tracing vital witnesses who resided abroad. He made several trips to Europe, during one of which he met Alexander Kerensky, the former premier of Russia, who became a good friend.
Simpson resigned from the United States attorney's office at the end of 1927 to become a partner in the firm of Barnes, McKenna & Halstead (later Barnes, Richardson & Halstead). Severing his connection with this firm in 1934, he joined Hunt, Hill & Betts, where he worked until 1939 when he formed the partnership of Simpson, Brady & Noonan.
As his legal career developed, Simpson became more and more engrossed with politics and rose to positions of leadership within the Republican Party. A liberal who believed his party had to abandon some of its conservative dogma to win and who exhibited a tolerance for the New Deal, Simpson served as president of his district club, 15th Assembly-District leader, and state committeeman. In 1935 Simpson was elected to the powerful position of Republican county chairman and from then on played a crucial role in rebuilding the New York Republican Party.
In 1937, Simpson orchestrated the reelection of Fusion Party candidate Mayor Fiorello LaGuardia with Republican Party endorsement. Simpson's efforts also insured the election of Republican candidates for president of the Board of Alderman and comptroller. Simpson also persuaded Thomas E. Dewey to run for the office of District Attorney and Bruce Barton to seek election to the House of Representatives from the 17th Congressional District. The success of these candidates marked Simpson as a political boss, and in December he was elected to the Republican National Committee to succeed Charles Dewey Hilles. Simpson worked hard in Dewey's unsuccessful gubernatorial bid in 1938, but by late 1939 Simpson had become disenchanted with him. Simpson saw Dewey as usurping his political authority and declared his opposition to Dewey's presidential bid in 1940. He played a vital role in nominating the liberal Wendell Wilkie and stopping Dewey. Simpson worked hard in Wilkie's unsuccessful campaign, while triumphing in his own bid for election from the 17th Congressional District. Shortly after being sworn-in as a member of the House of Representatives, Simpson died of a heart attack on January 25, 1941.
In 1925 Simpson married Helen-Louise Knickerbocker Porter. They had four children. In addition to his political achievements, Simpson and his wife contributed to the civic organizations and cultural life of New York. He was a member of the Player's Club, the Grand Street Boys' Association, and the Friendly Sons of St. Patrick and was a patron of music and a collector of modern art. He numbered among his friends cultural leaders such as Norman Bel Geddes, Gilbert Seldes, and Gertrude Stein.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, political memoranda, campaign literature, and printed matter documenting Kenneth Simpson's career as chairman of the Republican County Committee in New York (1935-1940). The papers also include case and client files from Simpson's legal practice. The papers highlight Simpson's support for Fiorello LaGuardia in the 1936 New York mayoral campaign, his opposition to Thomas E. Dewey's candidacy for presidential nomination in 1940, and his own successful campaign for election to the United States House of Representatives from the Seventeenth Congressional District of New York in 1940.
Arrangement
Arranged in six series: I. Correspondence, 1913-1941. II. Political Papers and Congressional Files, 1934-1941. III. Writings, 1936-1941. IV. Case and Client Files, 1923-1941. V. Personal Papers and Photographs, 1900-1983. VI. Scrapbooks, 1925-1941.
Law; New York (N.Y.) -- Politics and government -- 1898-1951; New York (State) -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950; United States -- Politics and government; Lawyers; Politicians; Barton, Bruce, 1886-1967; Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971; Dudley, Dorothy, 1884-; Geddes, Norman Bel, 1893-1958; Hilles, Charles Dewey, 1867-1949; Isaacs, Stanley M. (Stanley Myer), 1882-1962; Kerensky, Aleksandr Fyodorovich, 1881-1970; La Guardia, Fiorello H. (Fiorello Henry), 1882-1947; Landon, Alfred M. (Alfred Mossman), 1887-1987; Léon, Maurice, 1880-; Matisse, Pierre, 1900-1989; Pinchot, Amos, 1873-1944; Simpson, Kenneth F. (Kenneth Farrand), 1895-1941; Toklas, Alice B., 1877-1967; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- )
- Correspondence, 1913-1941; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series is composed of incoming and outgoing letters of both a personal and political nature. Correspondence with clients is included in the case and client files in Series IV. The correspondence is arranged in chronological order, and until 1934 there is little that relates to politics. Letters in 1913 from his father date from Simpson's freshman year at Yale, while the 1925 files contain messages of congratulation on his engagement.
  The files become more voluminous after Simpson's appointment as county chairman of the Republican Committee of New York County in September, 1935. Though the files do contain some exchanges with other Republican Party leaders such as Alfred Landon, Charles Dewey Hilles, Amos Pinchot, and Stanley M. Isaacs, which contain discussions of campaign strategy or policy matters, congratulatory messages from acquaintances and the general public form the bulk of the series. In 1937 there are letters of opinion concerning Republican support for the reelection of Fiorello LaGuardia, and 1938 letters contain voters' views of the candidacy of John O'Connor for Congress. In the 1939 files there are letters concerning organizational work for primaries and the efforts to unseat Simpson as Republican county committeeman. Strife within the party is further reflected in the correspondence of April, 1940, when Simpson faced an attempt to force him off the Republican National Committee. The files later in 1940 bulk large with letters concerning Wilkie's nomination and campaign for president, Simpson's own nomination and successful campaign for Congress, and the flattering portrait of Simpson published in Life magazine.
  The files include letters from close personal friends, such as Norman Bel Geddes, Maurice Leon, and Lyttleton Gould concerning many topics. The series concludes with several folders of correspondence with Dorothy Dudley Harvey and a file of letters concerning candidates for admittance to the bar. Simpson served as the legal advisor to Harvey, an author, and her husband. Papers concerning this professional relationship are found in Series IV. The correspondence in this series is strictly personal, is much larger than that with any of Simpson's other correspondents, and reflects their long and close relationship.
  - 1913 Sep, 1920-1928, 1930-1937 (Box 1, Folder 1-27)
  - 1937 October - December 22 (Box 2, Folder 28-53)
  - 1937 December 23 - 1939 August (Box 3, Folder 54-79)
  - 1939 September - 1940 August (Box 4, Folder 80-109)
  - 1940 September - October (Box 5, Folder 110-134)
  - 1940 November - December 7 (Box 6, Folder 135-163)
  - 1940 December 10 - 1941 Jan, undated (Box 7, Folder 164-175)
  - Harvey, Dorothy Dudley, 1930-1940, undated (Box 8, Folder 176-179)
  - Recommendations to the bar, 1932-1938 (Box 8, Folder 180)
- Political Papers and Congressional Files, 1934-1941; Series II
  This series consists of notes, drafts of policy papers, financial papers, election statistics, campaign literature and other printed ephemera, press releases, and newspaper stories, which relate to Kenneth Simpson's involvement in New York City Republican Party politics, national presidential campaigns, and his own campaign for congress in 1940. The files also include constituent correspondence and notes relating to legislation generated during Simpson's brief tenure in the House of Representatives. The scrapbooks in Series VI cover similar topics.
  The political papers are organized chronologically and the earliest date from 1934 when Simpson served on a committee investigating taxicab service. The files for the mayoral campaign of 1937 contain many statements by Simpson as he attempted to secure Republican Party endorsement for Fiorello LaGuardia for mayor. The most numerous files are those for 1940, covering Simpson's split with Thomas Dewey, his support for Wendell Wilkie for the presidential nomination, and his campaign for the 17th Congressional District seat.
  The series concludes with congressional files from Simpson's three weeks in Washington. Most of the constituent mail concerns "Lend-Lease" legislation, H.R. 1776, providing aid to Great Britain. Simpson favored passage of some form of this bill, but his constituent mail provides a view of the opposition's arguments as well as the broader scope sought by many supporters.
  - Political Papers
    General
    See also: Series IV. Scrapbooks
    - 1934 [Mayor's Committee on Taxicab Survey] (Box 9, Folder 1 - 3)
    - 1936
      - General (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Presidential campaign (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 1937
      - General (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - New York mayoral campaign
        - General (Box 9, Folder 7)
        - Simpson statements and press releases (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - 1938
      - General (Box 9, Folder 9)
        See also: Oversize, folder 2-3
        - Oversize (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Analysis of vote for assemblyman (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Analysis of vote for governor (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - New York Sixteenth Congressional District campaign (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - 1939
      - General (Box 10, Folder 13 - 14)
        - Oversize (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Primary (Box 10, Folder 15 - 16)
    - 1940
      - General (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - New York Fourteenth Congressional District special election (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - New York Seventeenth Congressional District election (Box 10, Folder 19 - 20)
        - Oversize (Box 37, Folder 2-3)
      - Republican presidential nomination
        - General (Box 10, Folder 21)
        - Convention petitions for members of the Committee on Resolutions (Box 10, Folder 22)
        - Dewey campaign materials (Box 10, Folder 23)
          - Oversize (Box 37, Folder 4)
        - Simpson split with Dewey
          - General (Box 10, Folder 24)
            - Oversize (Box 37, Folder 5)
          - Scrapbook of clippings from the Newark Star Ledger concerning the campaign to win New Jersey for Wendell Wilkie [compiled by Morris Mogelever] (Box 11, Folder 25)
        - Republican presidential campaign (Box 12, Folder 26)
      - undated (Box 12, Folder 27 - 28)
  - Congressional Files, 1941
    - Applicants for employment (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Constituent mail
      - General (Box 12, Folder 30)
      - Dies Committee (Box 12, Folder 31)
      - H.R. 1776
        - Against
          - A-M (Box 12, Folder 32 - 35)
          - N-Z, unidentified (Box 13, Folder 36 - 37)
        - For (Box 13, Folder 38 - 40)
        - Petitions for and against (Box 13, Folder 41 - 42)
      - Requests (Box 13, Folder 43)
      - St. Lawrence Seaway (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - Form letters (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - Legislation introduced [H.R. 2095] (Box 13, Folder 46)
- Writings, 1936-1941; Series III
  This series is composed of speeches and statements given by Simpson during the course of various political campaigns. The largest portion of these date from Simpson's own campaign for election in 1940. The materials are arranged in chronological order.
  - 1936 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1937 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1938 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 1939 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - 1940 (Box 14, Folder 5 - 9)
    General note
    See also: Historical Sound Recordings, Yale University Library for audio transcription of KFS's remarks at the Wilkie rally of November 2, 1940, in New York City.
  - 1941 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - undated (Box 14, Folder 11 - 12)
- Case and Client Files, 1923-1941; Series IV
  This series includes notes, letters, drafts for briefs, published material, and other types of papers relating to Kenneth Simpson's legal practice. Though there are files for cases or clients Simpson represented in each of his positions and partnerships including his work with the United States district attorney's office, the files do not appear to be comprehensive, and it is not clear what portion of Simpson's case load is represented. The files are arranged in alphabetical order by case or client name.
  Most of the files document fairly routine legal matters such as wills, divorces, estate settlements, receiverships, actions for rent, and the like. Among the files one finds the names of many prominent cultural figures whom Simpson advised or represented including Edmund Wilson, Dorothy Dudley Harvey, Evangeline Stokowska, Mary Mayo, Alexander Kerensky, Gilbert Seldes, and Pierre Matisse. Files of Andrew Somers relate to Simpson's work as counsel to the congressman during the proceedings instituted to impeach U. S. District Judge Grover Moscowitz. There are also several files for Flo Renyx, a Republican Party activist, concerning her role as a receiver in several cases. Many other files relate to Simpson's own participation as a receiver or court appointed special guardian.
  - American Patents Development Corporation [Ash Reclaiming Machinery Corporation], 1928 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Armone, Steve, 1934-1937 (Box 15, Folder 2 - 5)
  - Batti, Jacques Albert Duteil, 1935-1936 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Beekman estate, 1935-1936 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Berkowitz, Hyman, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Blackmer, H. M., 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Bodmer, Carol, 1928 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Brewster, Henry D. and Mary E. estates, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 11 - 12)
  - Brown, Leon, 1929 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Buck, Richard C., 1923 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Central Hanover Bank vs. Williams [Oliver Cromwell Hotel], 1935-1936 (Box 16, Folder 15 - 16)
  - City Bank Farmers Trust Company vs. Alice Chapin Evans, et al., 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Clayburgh, Alma, 1936-1937 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Colgate, Gilbert, Jr., 1928-1930 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Condé Nast Publications, Inc., 1935-1936 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Coty estate, 1934-1937 (Box 16, Folder 21 - 22)
  - Coty estate, 1934-1937 (Box 17, Folder 23 - 29)
  - Coty estate, 1934-1937 (Box 18, Folder 30 - 38)
  - Coty estate, 1934-1937 (Box 19, Folder 39 - 40)
  - Daly Daniel F., 1924 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - DeWolfe, Jacques, 1933-1934 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Dodd, John M. estate, 1937 (Box 19, Folder 43 - 45)
  - Dollar Savings Bank vs. Ruggerio [KFS referee], 1936 (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Dumont, Henry, 1928 (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Duncan, Henry, 1930-1933 (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - Duncan, Henry, 1930-1933 (Box 20, Folder 49 - 50)
  - Esposito, Ferdinando, 1923-1925 (Box 20, Folder 51 - 52)
  - Farrand, Mary Stevens estate, Circa 1936 - 1938 (Box 20, Folder 53)
  - Fay, Bernard, 1929-1936 (Box 20, Folder 54)
  - Fischman, Barnett, 1933-1936 (Box 20, Folder 55)
  - Fisher, Moe J. estate, 1933-1936 (Box 20, Folder 56)
  - Fowler, Mabel C., 1933-1935 (Box 20, Folder 57)
  - Franklin Plan Corporation, 1933-1935, 1941 (Box 20, Folder 58)
  - Friedman, Bernard J., 1929-1930 (Box 21, Folder 59)
  - Freleigh, Virginia [client of William Meekins], 1928 (Box 21, Folder 60)
  - Gates, Artemus L. and Wallace Hoggson, 1923-1924 (Box 21, Folder 61)
  - Gen Pharmacy, Inc., et al., 1930 (Box 21, Folder 62)
  - Gordon, George E. estate, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 63)
  - Hahn vs. Duveen [client of Michel Brault], 1936-1937 (Box 21, Folder 64)
  - Hamersley, John W. estate, 1934-1941 (Box 21, Folder 65 - 66)
  - Harvey, Dorothy Dudley, 1932 (Box 21, Folder 67)
  - Harvey, Dorothy Dudley and Henry B., 1934-1938 (Box 21, Folder 68)
  - Harvey, Henry B., 1927-1934 (Box 21, Folder 69 - 70)
  - Harvey, Henry B., 1927-1934 (Box 22, Folder 71 - 73)
  - Hatmaker, Consuele, 1930 (Box 22, Folder 74)
  - Haubrick, Frank, 1928 (Box 22, Folder 75)
  - Heller, Ernestine, 1928 (Box 22, Folder 76)
  - Hellstern & Co. [client of Michel Brault], 1936 (Box 22, Folder 77)
  - Johnson, Albert, 1927-1930 (Box 22, Folder 78 - 83)
  - Johnson, Albert, 1927-1930 (Box 23, Folder 84 - 85)
  - Keech, Gilbert W., Jr., 1938 (Box 23, Folder 86)
  - Kennard, R. Parry, 1935-1938 (Box 23, Folder 87)
  - Kerensky, Alexander, 1934-1939 (Box 23, Folder 88)
  - Klein, Erika [friend of Evangeline Stokowska], 1935 (Box 23, Folder 89)
  - Law, Robert M., 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 90 - 93)
  - Levy, Mansfield, 1927 (Box 24, Folder 94)
  - Lewis, Albert Nelson, 1936-1937 (Box 24, Folder 95)
  - MacFarlane, Edna Falls Ballagh, 1924-1926, 1936 (Box 24, Folder 96)
  - MacLeish, Charlotte E. D. estate, 1936 (Box 24, Folder 97)
  - Manville, Louis Arline, 1930-1935 (Box 24, Folder 98)
  - Marshall, Arthur A., 1927-1931 (Box 24, Folder 99 - 102)
  - Marshall, Arthur A. [re Bernard Schlenger], 1928-1931 (Box 24, Folder 103 - 104)
  - Matisse, Pierre, 1936-1938 (Box 24, Folder 105)
  - Mayo, Margaret, 1936-1937 (Box 24, Folder 106)
  - McGuire, William G., 1932-1934 (Box 25, Folder 107)
  - McLellan Stores Company, 1934-1936 (Box 25, Folder 108 - 110)
  - Meshel, David, 1930 (Box 25, Folder 111)
  - Morin S. Hare & Co., 1923-1924 (Box 25, Folder 112 - 113)
  - Motion Picture Corporation of America [John H. Green], 1936-1939 (Box 25, Folder 114)
  - Murvihill, Mabel, 1933-1935 (Box 25, Folder 115)
  - Nathan, Anna vs. Taps Medicine Co., Inc. [KFS receiver], 1929-1935 (Box 25, Folder 116)
  - National City Bank of New York et al. vs. Charles D. Waggoner et al., 1931-1935 (Box 25, Folder 117)
  - National City Bank of New York et al. vs. Charles D. Waggoner et al., 1931-1935 (Box 26, Folder 118 - 121)
  - New York Title & Mortgage Co. vs. 1576 Taylor Ave., 1934-1937 (Box 26, Folder 122)
  - Onward Construction Co. [Ansonia Hotel], 1933-1935 (Box 26, Folder 123 - 124)
  - 150 East Fifty-Fourth Street Corporation, 1930 (Box 26, Folder 125)
  - Oppenheimer, Leo, 1932 (Box 26, Folder 126)
  - Parkhurst, Helen, 1932-1934 (Box 26, Folder 127 - 130)
  - Peck, Samuel estate, 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 131 - 132)
  - Phillips H. Lord, Inc., 1935 (Box 27, Folder 133)
  - Plimpton, Helen Sheppard, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 134)
  - Porter, Mrs. George F., 1927-1929 (Box 27, Folder 135)
  - Porter, Nathan S. and Caroline C. A. [Bowery Savings Bank vs. Loburn Realty Corporation, et al.], 1933-1934 (Box 27, Folder 136)
  - Reed, Louis S., 1934 (Box 27, Folder 137)
  - Renyx, Flo [receiverships], 1933-1936 (Box 27, Folder 138 - 142)
  - Renyx, Flo [receiverships], 1933-1936 (Box 28, Folder 143 - 146)
  - Roscoe, Carolynne, Chitwood, 1928-1933 (Box 28, Folder 147)
  - Rosenzweig, Oscar, 1928-1929 (Box 28, Folder 148)
  - Roux, Gaston estate [client of Michel Brault], 1936 (Box 28, Folder 149)
  - Rowntree, Carlisle, 1927-1928 (Box 28, Folder 150 - 153)
  - S. R. Dresser Manufacturing Co. [H. N. Mallon], 1937 (Box 28, Folder 154)
  - Saxe Somogyi Co., Inc. vs. New York Men's Association, 1934 (Box 28, Folder 155 - 156)
  - Schlesinger & Company, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 157)
  - Seldes, Gilbert, 1937-1938 (Box 29, Folder 158)
  - Shepard, Frank P., 1923 (Box 29, Folder 159)
  - Silverglate, Jack, 1929-1930 (Box 29, Folder 160)
  - Smith, Isidor R. estate, 1938 (Box 29, Folder 161)
  - Smith, Snell, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 162)
  - Somers, Andrew L. [re Grover M. Moscowitz], 1929-1932 (Box 29, Folder 163 - 168)
  - Steinert, Alexander Lang, 1936-1941 (Box 29, Folder 169 - 170)
  - Stephenson, Hubert, 1926-1927 (Box 30, Folder 171)
  - Stewart, Donald Ogden, 1929-1933 (Box 30, Folder 172)
  - Stilwell, Jaynes & Co., 1927-1928 (Box 30, Folder 173 - 175)
  - Stokowska, Evangeline, 1929-1930 (Box 30, Folder 176)
  - Strachey, Esther Murphy, 1932-1933 (Box 30, Folder 177)
  - Turbine Equipment Company, 1924-1929 (Box 30, Folder 178 - 180)
  - Turbine Equipment Company, 1924-1929 (Box 31, Folder 181 - 183)
  - Van Nostrand, Louise B., 1935-1936 (Box 31, Folder 184)
  - Volga Kama Commercial Bank, 1936-1939 (Box 31, Folder 185)
  - Wallace, Grace estate, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 186)
  - Watkins, Beulah, 1932-1937 (Box 31, Folder 187 - 190)
  - Wertheim, Ruth [later Ruth Wertheim Smollens], 1934-1939 (Box 32, Folder 191 - 192)
  - Williams, Frank Starr, 1923-1924 (Box 32, Folder 193)
  - Wilson, Edmund, 1938 (Box 32, Folder 194)
  - Wilson, Mary Blair, 1929-1930, 1938 (Box 32, Folder 195)
  - Woosley, Myrtle Forney, 1930 (Box 32, Folder 196)
  - Zeppa, Francesco, 1930-1937 (Box 32, Folder 197)
  - Miscellaneous, 1927-1938 (Box 32, Folder 198)
  - Unidentified, Circa 1930-1937 (Box 32, Folder 199 - 200)
- Personal Papers and Photographs, 1900-1983; Series V
  This series is composed of papers which relate to Kenneth Simpson's day to day activities. They are more general in nature than the political papers and case and client files contained in the previous series. The few legal files in the series concern personal matters of Simpson and his family. Materials in the series are arranged by record type and are listed in alphabetical order. The largest categories of records are the financial papers and memorabilia. The financial papers include account books, check counterfoils and other records of the Simpsons' investments and household expenses. Included in the folders of memorabilia are programs and other types of printed ephemera from social, political, and cultural events attended by Simpson including the 1939 New York World's Fair and the Republican National Convention in 1940.